(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter
どこへ行ったの？
Where did you go?
聞こえますか？
Can you hear me?
あとどれだけ叫べばいいんだろう
How much more do I have to shout?
あとどれだけ泣けばいいんだろう
How much more do I have to cry?
もうやめて　私はもう走れない
Please stop, I can't run anymore.
いつか夢見た世界が閉じる
The world I once dreamed of is closing.
真っ暗で明かりもない
It's pitch black, with no light at all.
崩れかけたこの道で
On this road that's starting to crumble.
あるはずもないあの時の希望が見えた気がした
I felt like I saw the hope of that time, which shouldn't even exist.
どうして
Why?
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter
懐かしい記憶
A nostalgic memory.
ただ楽しかったあの頃を
Of those days when things were just fun.
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter
でも動けないよ
But I can't move.
闇を駆ける星に願いを
I make a wish to a star racing through the darkness.
もう一度だけ走るから
Because I'll run just one more time.
怖くて震える声でつぶやく
I whisper with a voice trembling with fear.
私の名前を呼んで
Call my name.
▽ ブラック★ロックシューター
▽ Black★Rock Shooter
どこへ行ったの？
Where did you go?
夜明けを抱く空
The sky embracing the dawn
境界線までの距離
The distance to the boundary
あと一歩届かない
Is still one step away
こらえた涙があふれそうなの
The tears I held back are about to overflow
今　下を向かないで
Now, don't look down
止まってしまう
Or you'll come to a halt
願いは生きていたいんだ
I wish to live on
わかったの
I've realized it now
思い出して　強く強く信じるの
Remembering, I believe strongly, so strongly
そうよ
That's right
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black★Rock Shooter
優しい匂い
A gentle scent
痛いよ　辛いよ
It hurts, it's painful
飲み込む言葉
The words I swallow
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black★Rock Shooter
動いてこの足
Move, these legs of mine
世界を超えて
Beyond the world!
最初からわかっていた
I knew it from the start
ここにいることを
That I was here
私の中のすべての勇気が
All the courage within me
火をともして
Lights a fire
もう逃げないよ
I won't run away anymore
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black★Rock Shooter
一人じゃないよ
You're not alone
声をあげて泣いたって構わない
It's okay to cry out loud
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black★Rock Shooter
見ていてくれる
You are watching over me
今からはじまるの
It's beginning from now
私の物語
My story!
忘れそうになったら
If I'm about to forget
この歌を
This song...
歌うの
...I'll sing
イエーイ！こんやっぴー！
Yay! Kon-yappi!
ホロライブ4期生の常闇トワ様でーす！
I'm Tokoyami Towa-sama from Hololive's 4th gen!
やっほー！イエーイ！
Yahoo! Yay!
はい！始まりました！
Yes! It has begun!
常闇トワ生誕祭2024！レッツゴー！
Tokoyami Towa Birthday Celebration 2024! Let's go!
ハッシュタグ「#常闇トワ生誕祭2024」で
Please tweet a lot with the hashtag
たくさん呟いてください！
#TokoyamiTowaBirthdayCelebration2024!
バシバシポストしてね！よろしく！
Post a lot, okay? Thank you!
目指せトレンド入り！ゴー！
Aiming for trending! Go!
ということで、えー、最初の1曲目、
So, the first song,
ブラック★ロックシューター、いかがでしたでしょうか？
Black★Rock Shooter, how did you like it?
演出がすごいカッコよかったでしょう？
The production was really cool, wasn't it?
えー、スタジオの皆さんが頑張ってもらいました。
Everyone at the studio worked hard.
運営さんね、頑張っていただきました！イエーイ！
The management worked hard too! Yay!
そのVJっていうかモニターがね、すごいカッコいいでしょ。
That VJ or monitor is really cool, right?
ほら見て！
Look!
このモニターが4分割になって、
This monitor splits into four,
くっついて…
then joins together...
ということで、結構ね、このモニターに
So there are quite a few tricks
仕掛けが今回はあるので…
with this monitor this time...
この後の曲、いっぱい歌うんですけど、
I'll be singing many songs after this,
どういう風な仕掛けがあるのかとかも
so I hope you enjoy watching while looking out
楽しみながら見ていただければと思います！
for what kind of tricks there are!
はい！そして今回のライブテーマは
Yes! And the theme of this live
「COLORFUL」になっておりまして、
is "COLORFUL",
1曲目がブラック★ロックシューターということで…
and the first song was Black★Rock Shooter...
えー、じゃあ、この後の曲、どんな曲名、
Well then, for the next songs,
どんな曲が、どんな曲が、
I wonder what titles, what songs, what songs,
どんな曲名が来るのかなーなんつってな！
what titles are coming! Just kidding!
はい！ということで、えー、ゲストもたくさん来るので、
Yes! So, many guests will also be coming,
お楽しみに！
so look forward to it!
はい！では皆さん、楽しんでいってください！
Yes! Well everyone, please enjoy!
早速、次の曲行ってみたいと思います！
Let's get right into the next song!
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
つまりは好奇心に囚われてたんだ
In other words, I was captivated by curiosity
大切なものなら壊したんだ
If it was something precious, I broke it
YELLOW
作詞・作曲：神山羊
Lyrics/Composition: Yoh Kamiyama
明かりの灯らないホールケーキ
A whole cake with no lights on
木製の君と踊ってたんだ
I was dancing with the wooden you
クローゼットで待って 今日も
Waiting in the closet, today as well
小さな体 寄せ合って
Huddling our small bodies together
眠るのさ
We'll sleep
変わるのさ
We'll change
想像 容易い 安全
Imagination, easy, safety
私馬鹿な子なの
I'm a foolish child
どこにも行かないで
Don't go anywhere
濁った正体の
Your muddy identity's
鈍い目を覚ませ
Waken those dull eyes
夜の内に片付けたおもちゃ
The toys I put away during the night
無邪気なままで まだ
Remaining innocent, still...
いたかった
I wanted to be
愛情は掃いて捨てるほどばかり
Affection is just something to sweep and discard
剥がれ落ちた 惨めな記憶
The miserable memories that have peeled off
バッドエンドなライフならばいっそ
If it's a bad-end life, then I'd rather...
ありえないこと願う夏を
Wish for an impossible summer
YELLOW
あいつは好奇心に殺されたようだ
Seems that guy was killed by curiosity
狡猾な術なら試したんだ
I tried some cunning methods
うだつの上がらないあんな行為
Such unpromising behavior
満面の笑みで歌ってたんだ
I was singing with a full smile
クローゼットで待って 今日は
Waiting in the closet, today...
一人で待つならこんなもんか
If I'm waiting alone, I guess this is it
変わるのさ
I'll change
終わるのさ
It'll end
肯定
Affirmation
求め続ける
Continuing to seek
カチカチ迫る秒針
The ticking hands of time closing in
まとまって 深くなって
Gathering, getting deeper
しまいにゃ手が落ち
In the end, my hands fall
逆さまになる
Turning upside down
なんでどうして
Why, how?
ほら霞んだ透明
Look, the hazy transparency
窓から見た景色をまだ覚えていますか
Do you still remember the view from the window?
いっそ消えてなくなるだけの
Just rather disappearing and being gone...
YELLOW
その日が来ないよう
So that day doesn't come
わざと間違えて
Purposefully making a mistake
崩れ落ちた 帰り途げだす
Crumbling down, starting the way home
救いなどないよ
There is no salvation
限りあるなんて
That there's a limit...
まだ 疼く 熱を
The throbbing heat I still feel...
愛情は掃いて捨てるほどばかり
Affection is just something to sweep and discard
剥がれ落ちた 惨めな記憶
The miserable memories that have peeled off
バッドエンドなライフならばいっそ
If it's a bad-end life, then I'd rather...
ありえないこと願う夏を
Wish for an impossible summer
オレンジ
作詞：MOMIKEN 作曲：UZ
Orange (オレンジ)
Lyrics: MOMIKEN / Composition: UZ
さよならは言わない
I won't say goodbye
約束もない
There's no promise
また会えるから
Because we can meet again
僕らは
We are
オレンジを少し
A little bit of orange
かじる地平線
The horizon being nibbled on
甘酸っぱい光
Sweet and sour light
眩しくて
It's so bright
すべり出す汗と
Sweat starts to slide
響いた声
The echoing voice
叩き合えた肩
The shoulders we patted
笑い合って泣いて
Laughing together and crying
明日へ向かう
Heading towards tomorrow
オレンジ色の
Orange-colored
空へ羽ばたいてゆく
Flying off into the sky
あと一秒だけ
Just one more second
もう一秒だけ
なんて惜しむような今が
Such a moment that I'm reluctant to leave...
きっと
Surely...
小さな背中に
On your small back
大きな夢を
A big dream
乗せてここまで来たんだよ
You've carried it all the way here
だらけの未来
A future full of...
だけじゃないけど
...is not all, but...
楽しかったよね　すべてが
it was fun, wasn't it? Everything.
息を切らした
Breathless,
走り続け
keeping on running,
追いかけてたのは　胸の熱さだろう
what I was chasing was likely the heat in my chest.
もう一回のない
There's no second time,
そんな時が
such moments...
ずっと繋がっていくように
so that they keep connecting forever.
何を描こうか？
What shall I draw?
何をしようか？
What shall I do?
なんて　想像してみるけど
I try to imagine, but...
きっと
Surely...
確かなことだって　いつかわかるから
Even certain things, I'll understand someday,
間違ってもいいよ　怖がらないで
it's okay to make mistakes, don't be afraid.
君は君でいい　oh
You're fine just being you, oh.
少し苦い　オレンジのよう
Like a slightly bitter orange,
後に残った切なさ
the sadness left behind.
あと1秒だけ
Just one more second,
もう1秒だけ
one more second,
なんて　慈しみながら行くよ
I'll go while cherishing them.
限られた時が　いつかふいに
The limited time, someday suddenly,
恋しくなっても
even if I start to miss it,
立ち止まらないで　振り返らないで
don't stop, don't look back.
君は進んで行けばいいのよ
You should just keep moving forward.
きっと
Surely...
桃源恋歌 作詞：メイリア 作曲：toku
Tougen Renka | Lyrics: MARiA | Composition: toku
見つめられたらそれだけで
Just being watched by you,
甘い花が香ります
sweet flowers give off their scent.
誰にも話しちゃいけないよ
You mustn't tell anyone,
夢なら覚めないで桃源郷
if it's a dream, don't wake me up, Shangri-La.
一口かじれば蜜の味
One bite, and it tastes of nectar.
やめないで戻れなくても
Don't stop, even if I can't go back.
ひらひら舞って落ちゆく
Fluttering and dancing, falling down,
染められて望みのままに
stained as I desire.
口付けたぐらいじゃ足りないわ
Just a kiss isn't enough,
夜が明けるまで踊りましょう
let's dance until the night breaks.
指と指を絡ませて
Intertwining finger with finger,
桃の雫飲み干せば
if I drink up the peach droplets,
このまま離れたくないとか
things like not wanting to leave you...
消えないで桃源郷
don't disappear, Shangri-La.
もう一口かじれば罪の味
One more bite, and it tastes of sin.
怖くないあなたとならば
It's not scary, if I'm with you.
はらはら咲いて散りゆく
Trembling as they bloom and scatter,
揺らされてこの恋心
this love heart, being shaken.
欲しがるは一つ貴方の愛
What I desire is only one thing: your love.
この身果てるまで歌いましょう
Let's sing until this body reaches its end.
ひらひら舞っては散りゆく
Fluttering and dancing, they fall and scatter
染められて望みのままに
Dyed as you wish
口づけくらいじゃ足りないわ
Just a kiss is not enough
愛に夜が明けるまで踊りましょう
Let's dance in love until the night gives way to dawn
ハナハナに咲いて散りゆく
Blooming in flowers, then falling and scattering
揺らされてこの恋心
This heart of love, swayed and shaken
もしもの一つ あなたへの愛に
If there's just one thing, in my love for you...
この身果てるまで歌いましょう
Let's sing until this body perishes
永遠に捧げましょう 嗚呼 愛に
Let's offer it up eternally, ah, to love
才能なんてないからここで一生泣いているんだろう
Since I have no talent, I'll probably be crying here for the rest of my life
目に映った景色の青さが羨ましく思っていた
I was envious of the blueness of the scenery reflected in my eyes
路傍に転がる人生 アスファルトの温度が合ってる
A life rolling by the roadside, the temperature of the asphalt suits me
迷子の顔照らす光を求め繋ぐ電波世界へと
Seeking the light that illuminates the faces of lost children, connecting to the radio wave world
Rainy Rainy 求めるものだけ描いた
Rainy Rainy, I drew only what I desired
心閉まって待って 本当は叫びたいのよ
Locking my heart away and waiting, but the truth is I want to scream
Rainy Rainy 強くなりたいと願った
Rainy Rainy, I wished to become stronger
これは無情に散って孤独を奏でる
This falls heartlessly and plays out my loneliness
指先から伝わっていく 鈍色の色
The dull gray color transmitted from my fingertips
認めてはくれないの？
Won't you acknowledge me?
くすんでしまったの灰色に こんな才能なんてありふれもの
It's become dull and gray; such talent is just a commonplace thing
まだ人生終わってないから 諦めんなって誰かの声
"Life isn't over yet, so don't give up," says someone's voice
見失ってしまったの藍色に 気づけなくて今も抗ってる
I've lost sight of the indigo blue; failing to notice, I'm still struggling even now
この感情奪い去ってよ ドロドロになってしまう前に
Snatch away these emotions before they turn into a muddy mess
Woah... 私だけ見て愛を伝えて
Woah... look only at me and tell me of your love
Woah... こんな世界とバイバイバイバイ
Woah... say bye-bye to a world like this
Woah... 滲む思いなぞって描いた
Woah... tracing the blurring thoughts, I drew
Woah... 夢の形に泣いちゃった
Woah... I ended up crying at the shape of my dreams
理解できると思ってた だけど現実は残酷だろう
I thought I could understand, but reality is cruel, isn't it?
焦りと不安のノイズの間に 黒くなって浮かんでいる
Between the noise of impatience and anxiety, it floats, turning black
退廃的なセンスと曖昧な表現なんかじゃ
With a decadent sense and vague expressions...
衒った奴らの荒らしに 飲み込まれて消えていく
...you'll be swallowed by the storm of those who show off and disappear
Rainy Rainy 雨が流れていくトローカー
Rainy Rainy, the rain flows through the trocar
肌を濡らして残った 冷たい記憶の体温
The temperature of cold memories left behind, soaking my skin
Rainy Rainy 雲の隙間から覗いた
Rainy Rainy, peeking through the gaps in the clouds
光が当たって届いて 体を軽くしたんだ
The light hit me and reached me, making my body feel lighter
美学とかプライドとか 語る前に
Before talking about aesthetics or pride...
揺れることやっていけ
...keep doing the things that sway you
焦がしてしまったの灰色に 剥げた才能一つ置いてけ
It's become scorched and gray; leave behind one piece of faded talent
誰だって同じなんでしょう？ 固まってる場合じゃないでしょう？
Everyone is the same, right? It's not the time to be frozen, is it?
目を開いても変わらない灰色に 気づいちゃってどうしようもないから
Even when I open my eyes, it's still gray; I've realized there's nothing I can do about it
それを虎視眈々と狙ってる ヴェルサイユなんて越されないよ
Vigilantly aiming for that, even Versailles won't surpass me
Woah... 私だけ見て愛を伝えて
Woah... look only at me and tell me of your love
Woah... こんな世界とバイバイバイバイ
Woah... say bye-bye to a world like this
Woah... 滲む思いなぞって描いた
Woah... tracing the blurring thoughts, I drew
Woah... 言葉の意味に泣いちゃった
Woah... I ended up crying at the meaning of the words
失くしてしまったのアイロニー この才能なんて光り物
The irony of what I've lost, this talent is just a shiny thing
まだ十全終わってないから 諦めんなって誰かの声
It's not completely over yet, "don't give up" says someone's voice
見失ってしまったのアイロニー 気付いてないふり笑ってる
The irony of what I've lost sight of, pretending not to notice and laughing
この感情奪い去ってよ 泥濘になってしまう前に
Take away these emotions, before they turn into a quagmire
私だけ見て愛を伝えて
Look only at me and convey your love
この世界とバイバイバイ
Say bye-bye-bye to this world
息も想いも滞って描いた
Breath and feelings stagnated as I drew
夢の形笑っていた
The shape of my dreams was laughing
鏡よ鏡よ鏡さん 世界で一番可愛いのは
Mirror, mirror, oh mirror, who's the cutest in the world?
やめてよ 棘のような視線刺さる
Stop it, those thorn-like gazes pierce through me
優しいふりした彼女が 素敵な晩餐もてなした
She, pretending to be kind, served a wonderful dinner
そっと口に含ませた 微笑
She softly put a smile into my mouth
薄れゆく意識の真ん中で
In the middle of my fading consciousness
夢を見てる いつかの おとぎ話
I'm dreaming of a fairy tale from sometime
時が止まる
Time stops
お願いキスで目を醒ましてほしいの
Please, I want you to wake me up with a kiss
白い棺桶から 連れ出すように
As if taking me out from the white coffin
突き刺さる憎しみはドラマティックな事情
The piercing hatred is a dramatic circumstance
彩っても 君はまだ来ない
Even if decorated, you haven't come yet
鏡よ鏡よ鏡さん 寝癖ネクタイ、微笑みさえ
Mirror, mirror, oh mirror, even my bedhead, tie, and smile
作るから 妬みを 買われてしまった?
I create them, so did I buy envy?
七つの小人はいるけど お助けそぶり知らんぷり
There are seven dwarfs, but they pretend not to help
そっと 首を掴まれ 微笑
Softly, my neck was grabbed, a smile
一粒の涙さえも
Even a single tear
拭えなくて 呼吸も ままならない
Can't be wiped away, I can't even breathe properly
視界 伏せた
Lowered my gaze
消えそうだから 早く駆けてほしいの
Because I'm about to disappear, I want you to run fast
訳は訊かないで 答えられない
Don't ask why, I can't answer
望まない憎まれは深い愛の事情
Unwanted hatred is a matter of deep love
もうすぐで いなくなるのかな?
I wonder if I'll be gone soon?
途切れてく命の灯
The light of life that is cutting out
毒リンゴを食した 少女のように
Like the girl who ate the poison apple
眠りに就く
Falling asleep
お願いキスで目を覚ましてほしいの
Please, wake me up with a kiss
胸の中の声 届きますか
Can you hear the voice inside my heart?
階段を登ったら ドアを開けるだけで
If I climb the stairs, just by opening the door...
見つかるよ
...I'll find it
お願いキスで目を覚ましてほしいの
Please, wake me up with a kiss
白い棺から連れ出すように
As if taking me away from a white coffin
突き刺さる憎しみは ドラマティックな事情
The piercing hatred is a dramatic circumstance
祈っても 君はまだ来ない
Even if I pray, you still don't come
消えてしまう
I'll disappear
その前に
Before that happens
イエーイ！
Yeah!
ウー！
Woo!
えーということで、ぶいすぽから
So, from VSPO!,
橘ひなのが来てくれましたー！
Hinano Tachibana has joined us!
こんにちは、こんばんはか
Hello, or is it good evening?
こんばんはー
Good evening!
ぶいすぽっ！の橘ひなですー！イエーイ！
I'm Hinano Tachibana from VSPO!! Yay!
どうだった？
How was it?
マジで疲れた！
I'm seriously tired!
いやでも、ホントに一緒に踊れてよかった
But I'm really glad we could dance together.
初めてだもんね、3Dでコラボするの
It's our first time collaborating in 3D, right?
そうなんですよ
That's right.
結構前に、3Dになったらコラボしようねって
A long time ago, we said let's collab when we're 3D.
まだその時には3Dになってなくて
We weren't 3D back then.
そうだっけ？
Was it like that?
そうだよ
Yeah, it was.
そうだわ
Oh, that's right.
ゲームしてる時にさ、してたそんな話
We talked about that while playing games.
そうそうそう
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
だから、3Dになった時コラボしようねって話をしてて、
So we were saying let's collab when we get 3D,
ウン年後、ついに呼んでいただけました
and years later, you finally invited me.
緊張してない？
Are you nervous?
ありがとうございます。ちょっと緊張してます。
Thank you. I'm a little nervous.
しかも疲れすぎだろ！
And you're way too tired!
疲れすぎだろ！
Too tired, right?
そりゃあ、トワさんはアイドルですけど、
Well, Towa-san, you're an idol, but
私は一般ゲーマーなんで、ちょっと体力のほうがね
I'm just a regular gamer, so my stamina is just...
自分の記念日とかに踊ったりしてたじゃん
But you've danced for your own anniversaries and such.
まあ、でもそんな…
Well, yeah, but still...
おばやめてよ
Stop acting like an old lady.
おばなんだから、しょうがない
I am an old lady, so it's only natural.
今日、トワは誕生日なんだけど
Today is Towa's birthday,
トワちゃん！
Towa-chan!
誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
イエーイ！
Yay!
欲しがり！欲しがりなのよ
Greedy! You're so greedy.
いつものやつね
Always the same old thing.
ちなみにこれ、ダンス練習一緒にやってて面白かったことがあったんだよね
By the way, something funny happened while we were practicing the dance.
言ってくださいよ
Please tell them.
サビに入る前に、私たちこうやって重なってたじゃないですか
Before the chorus, we were overlapping like this, right?
私、あの時前だったっけ？
Was I in front then?
1サビ前がトワが前で、こういう感じだよね
Before the first chorus, Towa was in front, like this.
で、2サビが反対なんだよね
And in the second chorus, it's the opposite.
私が後ろで、本当はこうなんだけど、
I was supposed to be in the back, like this,
なんか勢い余って、同じ角度で
but with too much momentum, I ended up at the same angle.
鏡を見て練習するんだけど、トワがこうやって顔が見えるんですよ
We're practicing looking in the mirror, and Towa can see her face.
でも目の前にひなのが同じポーズでこうなってるから、
But Hinano is right in front of me in the same pose,
「え、見えない！」ってなって、全く見えなくて
so I was like, "Wait, I can't see!" I couldn't see anything.
それでしばらくツボってたよね
We were laughing about that for a while.
だいぶツボって、そのあと普通に合ってるのに、
We were laughing so hard. Then, even though it was right,
「あれ、あれ？」みたいになってたんだけど
it was like, "Wait, is this right?"
ずっと引っ張ってたんですけど、今日はできてよかったです
We kept that joke going, but I'm glad we could do it today.
よかったです、できて
I'm glad we could.
ということで、今日は8月8日なんですけれども
So, today is August 8th,
なんと今月末にはぶいさいっていうのがありまして
and at the end of this month, there's V-Saikyo.
今日は仲良く踊って歌ったんですけど、ライバルになります
We sang and danced together today, but we'll be rivals there.
お互いリーダー枠ですもんね
We're both leaders, after all.
去年、去年もね、私もあなたもちょっと、やめようやめよう
Last year... both of us had... let's not talk about it.
やめよう！
Let's not!
お互いライバルだけど、払拭しよう、去年のを
Even though we're rivals, let's clear away last year's feelings.
ライバルだけど頑張りましょうね
Let's do our best as rivals.
ぶいさもよろしくお願いします
Good luck with V-Saikyo too.
お願いします
Good luck.
じゃあ、次の曲へどうぞって一緒に言ってもらえますか？
Then, could you say "Please enjoy the next song" with me?
もちろん
Of course.
お互いに好きなポーズしよう
Let's do our favorite poses.
これ、仲良し度大事だから、これ
This is important for showing our friendship.
せーの、次の曲へどうぞ！
One, two, please enjoy the next song!
（笑い声）
(Laughing)
違ったんだ。
That wasn't it.
間違えましたー。
I made a mistake!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
永遠の銀
Eternal Silver
作詞・作曲：kemu (kemu vox)
Lyrics & Composition: kemu (kemu vox)
残された呼吸を使い果たせば
If I use up my remaining breath
抱きしめた記憶さえ灰へと散る
Even the memories I held close will scatter into ash
鼓動と呪いだ、と気付きながら
While realizing it's a heartbeat and a curse
鮮烈な嘲笑、映らない棺
A vivid sneer, a coffin that doesn't reflect
その叫びを待って過去に溶ける
Waiting for that cry, it melts into the past
暗室の花だけを道連れに
Taking only the flowers from the darkroom with me
嫌だよ、終わるために生まれた秘境など
I hate it, a secret region born only to end
息を止めて、そのままで、命よ銀に枯れ
Hold your breath, just as you are, let life wither into silver
果てなき夢がいつまでも続きますように
May the endless dream continue forever
消えたくないよ、消えないで、ただそれだけを祈った
I don't want to disappear, don't disappear, I prayed for just that
最後、最後の幸せ
The last, the last happiness
誰にも、誰にも奪わせない
I won't let anyone, anyone take it away
離さない
I won't let go
作られた世界はどちらだろうか
Which one is the created world?
目を逸らし死神に問われたのは
Turning my eyes away, what the reaper asked me was...
濡れる陽の鮮やかさを手に囃す頃
When praising the vividness of the wetting sun in my hands
白楼は泣き続ける、その結末を思い出せ
Hakurou keeps crying, remember that ending
朝を迎えるのはあと何日だろう
How many days left until morning?
残された時間はあと何秒だろう
How many seconds left of the time?
この心が満たされるのはあと何秒だろう
How many more seconds until this heart is satisfied?
何秒だろう
How many more seconds?
願いよ届かずに、朽ちていく砂時計
May the wish go unheard, the hourglass rotting away
息を止めて、そのままで、命よ銀に枯れ
Hold your breath, just as you are, let life wither into silver
優しい歌がいつまでも響きますように
May the gentle song echo forever
悲しみもいつか去るのなら、いつかまで送りかえそう
If sadness will also leave someday, let's send it back until then
こんなに、こんなに、ささやかだ
It's so, so modest
最後、最後の願い事
The last, the last wish
いつか奏でる日々だけが続けばよかった
I wish only the days played someday would continue
それを守るだけの力が在ればよかった
I wish I had the strength just to protect that
澄んだ夕風をずっと見ていたかった
I wanted to keep looking at the clear evening breeze
それを守るだけの力が在ればよかった
I wish I had the strength just to protect that
いつか奏でる日々だけが続けばよかった
I wish only the days played someday would continue
それを守るだけの力が在ればよかった
I wish I had the strength just to protect that
澄んだ夕風をずっと見ていたかった
I wanted to keep looking at the clear evening breeze
それを守るだけの力が在ればよかった
I wish I had the strength just to protect that
いつか奏でる日々だけが続けばよかった
I wish only the days played someday would continue
それを守るだけの力が在ればよかった
I wish I had the strength just to protect that
全てを捧げても
Even if I sacrifice everything
息を止めて、そのままで、命よ銀に枯れ
Hold your breath, just as you are, let life wither into silver
果てなき夢がいつまでも続きますように
May the endless dream continue forever
消えたくないよ、消えないで、ただそれだけを祈った
I don't want to disappear, don't disappear, I prayed for just that
最後、最後の幸せ
The last, the last happiness
それでも、それでも、触れるなら
Still, still, if I touch...
許さない
I won't forgive
強くなれる理由を知った
I found a reason to become stronger
僕を連れて進め
Take me with you and move forward
紅蓮華
作詞：LiSA　作曲：草野華余子
Gurenge
Lyrics: LiSA  Composition: Kayoko Kusano
泥だらけの走馬灯に酔う
Drunk on a revolving lantern caked in mud
こわばる心 震える手は
My stiffened heart and trembling hands
掴みたいものがある それだけさ
Have something they want to grab onto, that's all
夜の匂いに空睨んでも
Even if I glare at the sky through the night's scent
変わっていけるのは自分自身だけ それだけさ
I'm the only one who can change myself, that's all
強くなれる理由を知った
I found a reason to become stronger
僕を連れて進め
Take me with you and move forward
どうしたって 消せない夢も
No matter what, even with dreams I can't erase
止まれない今も
And the present I can't stop
誰かのために強くなれるなら
If I can become stronger for someone's sake
ありがとう 悲しみよ
Then thank you, sadness
世界に打ちのめされて負ける意味を知った
Battered by the world, I learned the meaning of defeat
紅蓮の華よ咲き誇れ
O crimson lotus flower, bloom in full glory
運命を照らして
Lighting up my destiny
イナビカリの雑音が耳を刺す 戸惑う心
The noise of lightning pierces my ears, my heart is confused
優しいだけじゃ守れないものがある わかってるけど
I know there are things I can't protect just by being kind
水面下で絡まる善悪
Good and evil entangled beneath the surface
透けて見える偽善に天罰
Divine punishment for the hypocrisy I see through
Tell me why, tell me why, tell me why, tell me why, I don't need you!
逸材に敷き詰められた 棘だらけの道も
Even the thorn-filled path laid out for the talented
本気の僕だけに現れるから
Will appear only because I'm serious
乗り越えてみせるよ
I'll show you I can overcome it
簡単に片付けられた 守れなかった夢も
Even the dreams I couldn't protect, cast aside so easily
紅蓮の心臓に根を囃し
Let them take root in my crimson heart
この地に宿って
And dwell in this ground
人知れずはかない 散りゆく結末
A transient end, scattering away unnoticed
無情に破れた 悲鳴の風吹く
Heartlessly torn apart, a screaming wind blows
誰かの笑う影 誰かの泣き声
The shadow of someone laughing, the sound of someone crying
誰もが幸せを願ってる
Everyone is wishing for happiness
どうしたって 消せない夢も
No matter what, even with dreams I can't erase
止まれない今も
And the present I can't stop
誰かのために強くなれるなら
If I can become stronger for someone's sake
ありがとう 悲しみよ
Then thank you, sadness
世界に打ちのめされて負ける意味を知った
Battered by the world, I learned the meaning of defeat
紅蓮の華よ咲き誇れ
O crimson lotus flower, bloom in full glory
運命を照らして
Lighting up my destiny
Yeah! Yeah!
やったぜ！
We did it!
ヤッホー！
Yahoo!
ということで、ENからべーが来てくれました！
So, Bae from EN has joined us!
来ちゃいました！ハコス・ベールズです！
I'm here! I'm Hakos Baelz!
先輩！お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Senpai! Happy Birthday!
テンション高けぇ！
So much energy!
Happy, happy, まくる, happy birthday!
Happy, happy, lots of, happy birthday!
Oh my thank you very much!
Happy Birthday!
いや本当に呼んでくれてありがとうございました！
Really, thank you so much for having me!
いやありがとうね！あのめちゃめちゃ仲良いんだよね？
No, thank you! We're actually really close friends, right?
あの本当に仲良くて
We're really close
実は本当に仲良くて
We're actually really close
結構焼肉に行くうんですよね？
We go out for yakiniku quite a bit, don't we?
もうルーティンになってますね本当に
It's really become a routine now
そう焼肉行って 焼肉屋さんでお会計…
Yeah, we go for yakiniku, and then at the yakiniku restaurant when we pay...
…着替えずにコンビニに寄って…
...without changing, we'd stop by a convenience store...
はい。
Yeah.
…アイス買って、アイス食べながら散歩して帰るみたいなの結構やってるんだけど…
...buy ice cream, and walk home while eating it... we do that quite often.
そうです！そうです！
That's right! That's right!
ま、こうね、なんか3Dライブだけだよね、コラボしての。
Well, it's only for 3D lives like this that we collab, right?
確かに！
True!
本当に最近なんかゲーム配信とかコラボしてないですよね。
We really haven't done any game stream collabs or anything lately.
そうなんよね。
That's true.
あの、カバー動画とかで結構ずっとお互いのチャンネルでコラボして…
I mean, we've collabed for a long time with cover videos on each other's channels...
うん。
Yeah.
そうだよね。一緒に「Re:Route」を3Dで歌って…
That's right. Singing "Re:Route" together in 3D...
…で、今日の「紅蓮華」ここで歌って。でもゲーム配信は…
...and singing today's "Gurenge" here. But for game streams...
…もっとゲームしよう！
...let's play more games!
そうだよね！
True!
そうだよね。そうなんですよね。
Right. That's right.
もっとゲームしよう！
Let's play more games!
ゲームを、じゃあ…
Games, then...
直近に…
Soon...
鼻水出た…
(Laughs) My nose is running...
はい。
Yes.
やりたいと思います！
I'd like to do it!
はい！ということで…
Okay! So...
ま、「紅蓮華」はね、あのベェが歌がね、上手でかっこいい声歌えるので…
Well, for "Gurenge", since Bae is a good singer and can sing with a cool voice...
…一緒に歌いたいと思って選びました。
...I chose it because I wanted to sing it together.
いやいやいや、何言ってるんですか！
No no no, what are you saying!
トワ先輩！先輩の方がね…
Towa-senpai! Senpai is the one...
…なんかそんな…こんなにかっこいい、大好きな先輩と…
...with such... with such a cool, favorite senpai...
…なんかこの…あの「紅蓮華」歌えてできて嬉しいです。とても。
...I'm happy to be able to sing "Gurenge" like this. Very.
ありがとう。
Thanks.
なんかちょっと恥ずかしいから次行くか。
It's a bit embarrassing, so shall we move on?
あ！
Ah!
あ、ということで、次の曲へ！
Ah, so, on to the next song!
どうぞ！
Here you go!
青のすみか
－作詞・作曲：Tatsuya Kitani－
Where Our Blue Is
- Lyrics & Composition: Tatsuya Kitani -
どこまでも続くようなあの季節は
That season that seemed to go on forever
いつ並ぶ まだこの前を遮るものは何もない
When lined up, there is still nothing blocking our path
アスファルト 蝉時雨を反射して
Reflecting off the asphalt and the chorus of cicadas
君という沈黙が聞こえなくなる
The silence that is you becomes inaudible
この日々が色褪せる
These days fade
僕と違う君の匂いを知ってしまっても
Even if I come to know your scent, different from mine
時をすべて期待の永遠の底に
Leaving all time at the bottom of an expected eternity
今でも青が澄んでいる
Even now, the blue still dwells
今でも青は澄んでいる
Even now, the blue is dwelling
どんな祈りも言葉も
No matter the prayers or words
近づけるのに届かなかった
They didn't reach, despite getting closer
まるで静かな恋のような
Just like a quiet love
頬を伝った夏のような色の中
Inside the color like a summer that trickled down my cheek
君を呪う言葉が
The words cursing you
ずっと喉の奥に閊えてる
Have always been stuck in the back of my throat
また会えるよねって
Saying "We'll meet again, right?"
声にならない声
A voiceless voice
昼下がり 沁みつく風の季節は
In the early afternoon, the season of the clinging wind
想い馳せる まだ何者でもなかった僕らの肖像
I think back to our portraits when we were still nobodies
何もかも分かち合えたはずだったあの日から少しずつ
From that day when we were supposed to share everything, little by little
君と違う僕という呪いが肥っていく
The curse that is me, different from you, grows larger
君の笑顔の奥の憂いを
The grief deep within your smile
見落としたこと 悔やみ尽くして
Regretting having overlooked it completely
徒花と咲いて散っていく
Blooming and falling like a fruitless flower
君にさよなら
Farewell to you
さよなら
Goodbye
今でも青が澄んでいる
Even now, the blue still dwells
今でも青は澄んでいる
Even now, the blue is dwelling
どんな祈りも言葉も
No matter the prayers or words
近づけるのに届かなかった
They didn't reach, despite getting closer
まるで静かな恋のような
Just like a quiet love
頬を伝った夏のような色の中
Inside the color like a summer that trickled down my cheek
君を呪う言葉が
The words cursing you
ずっと喉の奥に閊えてる
Have always been stuck in the back of my throat
また会えるよねって
Saying "We'll meet again, right?"
声にならない声
A voiceless voice
無限に膨張する銀河の星の粒のように指の隙
Like grains of stars in a galaxy expanding to infinity, between my fingers...
...のはこぼれた
...overflowed.
はい！『青のすみか』でしたー！
Yes! That was "Ao no Sumika"!
どうだったみんなー？
How was it, everyone?
ありがとう。
Thank you.
あ、かっこよかった？
Oh, was it cool?
Thank you, ありがとう。
Thank you, thanks.
もうかっこいい曲だからね、すごい歌いたかったんで、今日歌えてよかったです。
It's such a cool song, I really wanted to sing it, so I'm glad I could today.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
そして！なんと、あと1曲歌います。まだ行かないでね。いい？
And! Believe it or not, I'll sing one more song. Don't leave yet, okay?
こちら、ラスト1曲は、なんと4月に募集した「アレンジソングコンテスト」の曲になっております！
This last song is actually from the "Arrange Song Contest" we held in April!
覚えている方いらっしゃいますでしょうか？
I wonder if anyone remembers that?
今日ね、歌わせていただきたいと思います。
I'd like to perform one today.
募集したのが『Purple Disease』と『Palette』っていうトワのオリジナルソングを募集したんですけど、
We were looking for arrangements of my original songs, "Purple Disease" and "Palette."
たくさんの応募がありました。ありがとうございます。
We received so many entries. Thank you so much.
今日ね、いやもう本当に、めっちゃいい曲が何曲もあったんですよ。
I mean, there were really so many great tracks.
で、絞るのがすごい、たくさん考えて考えて、1曲「これだ！」「もうこれだ！」っていうのを決めて、
It was so hard to narrow it down, but after a lot of thought, I picked this one!
今日この配信で1曲歌うのと、
I'll sing one during this stream,
あとこの後のメンバーシップ配信の限定の配信でもう1曲歌うので、
and another one during the membership-only stream afterwards.
この後のメン限のアンコールライブもぜひ皆さん見てってください！
So please check out the membership encore live too!
はい。で、この配信で歌うのは、
Okay. And the one I'll sing now is...
r0yさんアレンジの『Purple Disease』を歌いたいと思います！
...the r0y remix of "Purple Disease"!
すごいかっこいい曲、もともとすごいかっこよかったんだけど、
It's a really cool track. It was already cool to begin with,
さらにスタイリッシュな感じのアレンジをしてくれているので、
but the arrangement makes it even more stylish.
ぜひ聴いていってくれたらなと思います。
I hope you all enjoy it.
よろしくお願いします！
Please enjoy!
はい。ということで、はい、グッズの情報は、
Right. Also, regarding the merch info,
一番最後にまとめてお送りするので、グッズ購入したいよーって方は最後までよろしくお願いします。
I'll go over it all at the very end, so stay tuned if you're interested!
ということで、ラストの曲、『Purple Disease』行きましょう！
So, here's the last song. "Purple Disease," let's go!
毒々しくなプラン
A poisonous plan
逆も情慈じゃあけ
Even the opposite is heartless
餌食してやる
I'll make you my prey
臓器まで蝕む
Corroding down to your organs
Yeah うるせえ精巧で 部屋
Yeah, shut up. In this exquisite room
愛情 維持 独り言
Affection, maintenance, soliloquy
ああ 営々でも
Ah, even if it's endless
Give me give me 君だけだ
Give me, give me, only you
視線気にするほど 暇じゃないの
I'm not so free as to care about gazes
獲物 独り占めする
Monopolizing the prey
無限軌道の刺激
The thrill of infinite orbit
優越感の夜 紫に怯えて
A night of superiority, trembling in purple
私を選んで
Choose me
幸せに後悔してよ
And regret it in happiness
落ちてよ これが
Fall for it, this is...
紫の魔術
...the purple magic
君の果実
Your fruit
やるの おもちゃの
Giving you a toy-like...
弄（いじ）じゃん
...manipulation, right?
毒物で完成
Completed with toxins
この手に苦い チョコレート
A bitter chocolate in this hand
知らない 媚薬
An unknown aphrodisiac
望（のぼ）せに酔いしれてよ ほら
Get drunk on the rush, look
未熟な覚悟構えてよ
Ready your immature resolve
Why, Why, Why
飲まれてたいでしょ
You want to be swallowed up, don't you?
Why, Why, Why
病まればいいよ
It's fine to fall ill
見逃す子守も 愚痴かも いいか
Overlooking the lullaby or grumbling, is it okay?
癒されたまま毒に 侵されていいの
Is it okay to be violated by poison while being healed?
破滅ってハッピーエンド
Destruction is a happy ending
不幸せって結構じゃん
Unhappiness is quite alright
誤魔化して網を
Deceive and set the net
窒死しろ 華美を
Suffocate the splendor
レットゴーてやつ
That thing called "let go"
耽溺せよ フレッシュだわ
Indulge yourself, it's fresh
君のこと分かってやる
I'll understand you
嫌えのレベル
The level of loathing
邪推(じゃすい)してみて
Try guessing with suspicion
指標下ろし
Lowering the index
深淵 見えりゃ
If you can see the abyss
火が 火が上がるんだ
The fire, the fire rises
何も知らないまま
Without knowing anything
君は救われているみたいに見えるんだ
You look like you're being saved
甘いこの牙の
With these sweet fangs'
バランス 隠したまま近づくんだよ
balance hidden, I'll draw near
私を選んで
Choose me
幸せに後開してよ
And regret it in happiness
落ちてよ これが
Fall for it, this is...
心の底を
...the bottom of your heart
こともなく蝕んでいくよ
Corrupting without a sound
欲を乞い 欲を乞い
Begging for greed, begging for greed
Leave it, Leave it, Leave it...
紫の捕食
Purple predation
太陽の捕食
Solar predation
空洞、空洞、泥魔、空洞
Hollow, hollow, mud demon, hollow
日差しのなか
In the sunlight
侵入して燃やす
Intruding and burning
Praying, praying, praying
犠牲 犠牲 犠牲
Sacrifice, sacrifice, sacrifice
軽率に手伸ばしてほら
Look, reaching out thoughtlessly
目眩の薄いところよ
A place where the dizziness is faint
Why, why, why?
止まらないでしょう
It won't stop, will it?
Why, why, why?
Purple Disease
止まらないでしょう
It won't stop, will it?
Why, why, why?
気の病
Sickness of the mind
Purple Disease Oh, oh, Purple Disease
Oh, oh, Purple Disease
ということで 本日は常闇トワ生誕祭2024を見てくれてありがとうございましたー！
And with that, thank you so much for watching Tokoyami Towa's Birthday Festival 2024 today!
いかがだったでしょうか？
How was it for you all?
たくさん感想やスクリーンショット、SNSなどに投稿していただければ嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if you'd post lots of impressions and screenshots on SNS and elsewhere!
そして、グッズのお知らせです！イエーイ！
And now, it's time for merchandise announcements! Yay!
今回のグッズのイラストは、rurudoママに描いていただきました！じゃーん！
The illustrations for this merchandise were drawn by rurudo-mama! Ta-da!
夏なので、えー、水着にしてみちゃいましたー！
Since it's summer, uh, I decided to go with a swimsuit!
はい。全部で4種類となっております。
Yes. There are four items in total.
ホログラムアクリルパネル、トワ様と春夏秋冬ランダム缶バッジ、
A hologram acrylic panel, Towa-sama & the Seasons random tin badges,
トワ様ぬいぐるみ Break Your Outfit ライブ衣装、
a Towa-sama plushie in her Break Your Outfit live costume,
眷属クリアショルダーバッグの4点となっておりまして、
and a Kenzoku clear shoulder bag. These four items,
単品購入もできますし、フルセットの購入もできます！
can be purchased individually or as a full set!
フルセットの場合、複製サインか、数量限定で
With the full set, you'll get a printed signature or, in limited quantities,
直筆サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードがついてきまーす！
a handwritten signed cheki-style bromide card!
はい。そして、グッズの詳細です！まず1点目、ドン！
Yes. And now for the merch details! First item, boom!
rurudoママ描き下ろし、ホログラムアクリルパネル！
Illustrated by rurudo-mama, the hologram acrylic panel!
キラキラのね、ホログラム仕様の水着トワ様を是非飾ってみてください！
Please display this sparkly hologram swimsuit Towa-sama!
めっちゃね、可愛く描いてもらったし、
It's drawn so cutely, and
このね、なんといっても後ろのビビの表情とか、それがね、
above all, the expression of Bibi in the back, and that,
ビビのモチモチ具合が可愛すぎるのよ！
Bibi's squishiness is just too cute!
なので是非チェックお願いします！そして2つ目、ドン！
So please check it out! And the second item, boom!
トワ様と春夏秋冬ランダム缶バッジ！
Towa-sama & the Seasons random tin badges!
こちらはね、しろ先生に描き下ろししていただいた
These are cute mini-character tin badges of the four seasons
春夏秋冬の可愛いミニキャラ缶バッジとなっております！
illustrated by shiro-sensei!
一つ一つね、服も違うデザインで、しろ先生が描き下ろししてくださって、
Each one has a different outfit design drawn by shiro-sensei,
可愛くしてもらってるので、是非チェックして、
and they're so cute, so please check them out and
どんな感じの服なのかなーとかを実物を見てみてほしいなと思います！
I hope you'll take a look at the real things to see the outfits!
男の子も女の子も是非ゲットしてほしいし、
I want both boys and girls to get them,
推しバッグを作ってほしいなと思ってます！
and I hope you'll make an 'oshi-bag' with them!
はい。そして3つ目、ドン！
Yes. And the third item, boom!
トワ様ぬいぐるみ Break Your Outfit ライブ衣装ー！ウィー！
A Towa-sama plushie in her Break Your Outfit live costume! Wee!
なんと、この後にも紹介するショルダーバッグに
Believe it or not, a plushie in a size that fits
入るサイズのぬいぐるみが登場！
into the shoulder bag I'll introduce later is here!
ソロライブ衣装のトワ様のぬいぐるみとなっております！
It's a Towa-sama plushie in her solo live costume!
こちら、細かいところもね、再現してくれているので、
They've even reproduced the fine details on this,
是非お手にとってチェックしてみてください！
so please get one and check it out!
はい、そして最後4つ目、ドン！
Yes, and finally the fourth item, boom!
眷属クリアショルダーバッグ！パフパフ！
The Kenzoku clear shoulder bag! Puff puff!
こちらは、先ほど紹介したソロライブ衣装の
This is designed to hold the solo live costume
トワ様のぬいぐるみが入る仕様となっておりまして、
Towa-sama plushie I just introduced,
もちろん、ホロライブフレンズもしっかり入る大きさのバッグとなっております！
and of course, it's also big enough to fit Hololive Friends!
男性でも女性でも使いやすいデザイン、カラーとなっておりますので、
The design and colors are easy for both men and women to use,
是非普段使いもしてください！
so please use it in your daily life!
ほい。そしてこちらが、フルセット特典のチェキ風ブロマイドカードです！
Okay. And here is the full set bonus cheki-style bromide card!
フルセットにはちょっと数量限定にはなりますが、
The full set, though in limited quantities,
直筆サインがついてくるので、是非この後の概要欄のサイトからチェックして購入してみてください！
comes with a handwritten signature, so please check the site in the description below!
ということで以上、グッズの告知でしたー！ありがとう！サンキュー！
And that's all for the merch announcements! Thank you! Thank you!
今日は、えー、本当にね、見に来てくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you so much, uh, for coming to watch today!
この後はメンバー限定でライブもするので、お楽しみにー！
I'll be doing a member-only live after this, so look forward to it!
まったねー！
See ya later!
常闇トワ生誕祭2024 / COLORFUL
Tokoyami Towa Birthday Festival 2024 / COLORFUL